Register of the Irwin T. and Shirley Holtzman collection, 1899-2010
Hoover Institution Archives
- Boris Pasternak File, 1910-1998.
  - Printed matter. Publications by and about Boris Pasternak, arranged chronologically. Boris Pasternak's name is omitted when he is the author. Hardback, unless otherwise indicated (Box 27)
    - General
      - Baratashvili, Nikolai, Stikhotvoreniia v perevode Borisa Pasternaka, Biblioteka Ogonek No. 9, 1946 (Box 29)
      - Boris Pasternak: Selected Poems, Stefan Schimanski, ed., Lindsay Drummond, Ltd., London, 1946 (Box 29)
      - Gruzinskie poety, Sovetskii Pisatel', 1946 (Box 29)
      - New Directions 9, 1946 (Box 29)
      - Accent, Autumn 1946 (Box 29)
      - Gamlet, translation of William Shakespeare's Hamlet, DETGIZ, 1947 (Box 29)
      - Gruzinskie poety: Izbrannye perevody, Zaria Vostoka, Tblisi, 1947 (Box 29)
      - Arena, 1948 (Box 29)
      - Bowra, C. M., The Creative Experiment, Grove Press Inc., 1948 (Box 29)
      - Izbrannoe, Sovetskii Pisatel', 1948 (Box 29)
      - A Second Book of Russian Verse, C. M. Bowra, ed., Macmillan and Co. Ltd., 1948 (Box 29)
      - Genrikh IV, translation of William Shakespeare's, Henry IV, OGIZ, 1949. (Box 29)
        Inscribed and signed for "Boria and Zhenia," 1949
      - Selected Writings, New Directions, 1949 (Box 29)
      - New Russian Stories, Bernard Guerney, ed., 1953 (Box 29)
      - Znamia, Moscow, 1954. (Box 29)
        Inscribed for Evgeniia Livanova
      - Gamlet, translation of William Shakespeare's Hamlet, DETGIZ, 1956 (Box 29)
      - "Izbrannye stikhi." Proof for collection of poems that was not published, 1957 (Box 29)
      - Sashin, Ian, Literaturnyi kompleks, Sovetskii Pisatel', 1957 (Box 29)
      - Shelli: Lirika, Moscow, 1957 (Box 29)
      - Tabidze, Titsiian, Izbrannoe, Zaria Vostoka, Tbilisi, 1957. (Box 29)
        Inscribed by Nina Tabidze and Boris Pasternak
      - L'An 1905, B. Goriély, trans., Debresse-Poésie, 1958 (Box 29)
      - Berger, Yves, Boris Pasternak, 1958 (Box 29)
      - Delo Pasternaka, Ts.OPE, 1958 (Box 29)
      - Essai d'autobiographie, Gallimard, 1958 (Box 29)
      - Récit, B. Goriély and M. Aucouturier, trans., Emmanuel Vitte, 1958 (Box 29)
      - Selected Poems, J. M. Cohen, trans., Ernest Benn Limited, 1958 (Box 29)
      - Safe Conduct, An Autobiography and Other Writings, New Directions Paperback, 1958 (Box 29)
      - Stikhi o Gruzii: Gruzinskie poety, Zaria Vostoka, Tbilisi, 1958 (Box 29)
      - Partisan Review, Fall 1958 (Box 29)
      - Encounter, 1958 November (Box 29)
      - Poems by Boris Pasternak, L. Slater, trans., Peter Russel, 1958-1959. (Box 30)
        Three copies, one inscribed by L. Pasternak-Slater
      - Bitter Harvest, Edmund Stillman, ed., 1959 (Box 30)
      - Columbia Review, 1959 (Box 30)
      - Crankshaw, Edward, Khrushchev's Russia, 1959 (Box 30)
      - An Essay in Autobiography, Manya Harari, trans., Collins and Harvill Press, 1959. (Box 30)
        Hardback and paperback copies
      - Fourteen Short Stories by Soviet Authors, George Reavey, ed., 1959 (Box 30)
      - I Remember: Sketch for an Autobiography, Manya Harari, trans., Pantheon, 1959 (Box 30)
      - The Last Summer, George Reavey, trans., 1959. (Box 30)
        Hardback and uncorrected proof, Peter Owen Limited, paperback and uncorrected proof Avon Books, paperback Penguin Modern Classics and Penguin Books
      - Pasternak: Prose & Poems, Stefan Schimanski ed., Ernest Benn Limited, 1959 (Box 30)
      - Poems by Boris Pasternak, Eugene Kayden, trans., University of Michigan Press, 1959 (Box 30)
      - The Poetry of Boris Pasternak 1917-1959, George Reavey, ed., G. P. Putnam's Sons (Box 30)
      - Quarterly Review, vol. 1, no. 2, 1959 (Box 30)
      - Ruge, Gerd, Pasternak: A Pictorial Biography, 1959 (Box 30)
      - Safe Conduct, Signet Books, 1959 (Box 30)
      - Safe Conduct: An Early Autobiography and Other Works, Alec Brown and Lydia Pasternak-Slater, trans., 1959. (Box 30)
        Hardback and advance proof copy
      - Approach, Spring 1959. (Box 30)
      - Literary Review, Spring 1959 (Box 30)
      - Encounter, 1959 June (Box 30)
      - Books Abroad, Winter 1959 (Box 30)
      - Faust, translation of Goethe's Faust, Moscow, 1960 (Box 31)
      - I Remember: Sketch for an Autobiography, Meridian Books Inc., 1960 (Box 31)
      - The Last Summer, Penguin Books, 1960 (Box 31)
      - Poems 1955-1959, Michael Harari, trans., Collins and Harvill Press, 1960 (Box 31)
      - Portfolio and Art News Annual, no. 4, 1960 (Box 31)
      - Encounter, 1960 August (Box 31)
      - The Paris Review, Summer-Fall 1960 (Box 31)
      - X: A Quarterly Review, vol. 1, 1960-1961 (Box 31)
      - The Adolescence of Zhenya Luvers. Hardback by Philosophical Library, paperback by Citadel Press, 1961 (Box 31)
      - Muchnic, Helen, From Gorky to Pasternak, 1961 (Box 31)
      - Partisan Review, nos. 3-4, 1961 (Box 31)
      - Payne, Robert, Boris Pasternak, 1961. (Box 31)
      - Pipes, Richard, ed., The Russian Intelligentsia, 1961 (Box 31)
      - Proza 1915-1958: Povesti, rasskazy, avtobiograficheskie proizvedeniia, G. Struve et al., eds., The University of Michigan Press, 1961. (Box 31)
        Hardback and uncorrected proof
      - Reavey, George, Modern Soviet Short Stories, 1961 (Box 31)
      - Stikhi 1936-1959: Stikhi dlia detei. Stikhi 1912-1957, ne sobrannye v knigi avtora. Stat'i i vystupleniia, G. Struve et al., eds., The University of Michigan Press, 1961. (Box 31)
      - Stikhi i poemy 1912-1932, G. Struve et al. eds., The University of Michigan Press, 1961. (Box 31)
      - Stikhotvoreniia i poemy, Moscow, 1961 (Box 31)
      - The Paris Review, Summer-Fall 1961 (Box 31)
      - Encounter, September 1961 (Box 31)
      - The Transatlantic Review, Winter 1961 (Box 31)
      - Conquest, Robert, Courage of Genius, 1961-1962 (Box 32)
      - Carlyle, Olga, Voices in the Snow, 1962 (Box 32)
      - Ehrenburg, Ilya, People and Life, 1962 (Box 32)
      - Fischer, M., Reunion in Moscow, 1962 (Box 32)
      - In the Interlude – Poems 1945-1960, Henry Kamen, trans., 1962. (Box 32)
        Includes hardback by Oxford University Press and paperback by Oxford Paperbacks
      - Sbornik statei posviashchennykh tvorchestvu B. L. Pasternaka, Munich, 1962 (Box 32)
      - Aucouturier, Michel, Pasternak par lui-même, 1963 (Box 32)
      - Brown, Edward, Russian Literature Since the Revolution, 1963 (Box 32)
      - Ehrenburg, Ilya, Eve of War 1933-41, 1963 (Box 32)
      - Fifty Poems, Lydia Pasternak Slater, trans., George Allen 8 Unwin Ltd. and Barnes & Noble Inc., 1963. (Box 32)
      - Mallac, Guy de, Pasternak, 1963 (Box 32)
      - Winter Festivities, Centaur Press, 1963 (Box 32)
      - Writers at Work: The Paris Review Interviews, 1963 (Box 32)
      - Commentary, February 1963 (Box 32)
      - Dissonant Voices in Soviet Literature, Max Hayward and Patricia Blake, eds., 1964 (Box 32)
      - Ehrlich, Victor, The Double Image: Concepts of the Poet in Slavic Literatures, 1964 (Box 32)
      - Poems by Boris Pasternak, Eugene Kayden trans., The Antioch Press, 1964 (Box 32)
      - Proyart, Jacqueline de, Pasternak, La Bibliothèque Idéale, 1964 (Box 32)
      - Partisan Review, Summer 1964 (Box 32)
      - Bolt, Robert, Doctor Zhivago: The Screenplay, 1965 (Box 33)
      - Gedichte von Jurij Schiwago, Possev-Verlag, 1965 (Box 33)
      - Hayward, Max and Edward Crowley, eds., Soviet Literature in the Sixties, 1965 (Box 33)
      - Karácsonyi Csillag: Kései Versek (1945-1960), Occidental Press, 1965 (Box 33)
      - Novyi Mir, 1965 (Box 33)
      - Reavey, George (Box 33)
        - The Poetry of Evgenii Evtushenko 1953 to 1965, October House Inc. (Box 33)
          Inscribed by the author
        - Soviet Literature Today, 1965. (Box 33)
      - Stikhotvoreniia i poemy, with an introduction by Andrei Siniavskii, Sovetskii Pisatel', 1965 (Box 33)
      - Vozdushnye puti: Al'manakh IV, 1965 (Box 33)
      - Great Stories by Nobel Prize Winners, L. Hamalian and E. Volpe, eds., 1966 (Box 33)
      - Modern European Poetry, Willis Barnstone, ed., 1966 (Box 33)
      - Muchnic, Helen, From Gorky to Pasternak, 1966 (Box 33)
      - Pire, Dominique, Building Peace, 1966 (Box 33)
      - Plank, Dale, Pasternak's Lyric: A Study of Sound and Imagery, 1966 (Box 33)
      - Stikhi, Khudozhestvennaia Literatura, Moscow, 1966 and 1967 (Box 33)
      - Tarasenkov, A., Russkie poety XX veka 1900-1955, Sovetskii Pisatel', 1966 (Box 33)
      - Zvezdnoe nebo: Stikhi zarubezhnykh poetov v perevode Borisa Pasternaka, Progress, Moscow, 1966 (Box 33)
      - Bowra, C. M., Memories, 1967 (Box 33)
      - Svetlana Allilueva B. L. Pasternaku, 1967 (Box 33)
      - New American Review, 1967 (Box 33)
      - Novyi Mir, 1967 (Box 33)
      - Rossiia rodina moia, Khudozhestvennaia Literatura, Moscow, 1967 (Box 33)
      - Rowland, Mary F. and Paul, Pasternak's Doctor Zhivago, 1967 (Box 33)
      - Sister My Life, Phillip C. Flayderman, trans., 1967. (Box 33)
      - Harvard Library Bulletin, 1967 October. (Box 33)
        Includes offprint
      - Letters to Georgian Friends, David Magarshack, trans., 1967-1968. (Box 33)
        Uncorrected proof. Includes Three Letters from Boris Pasternak, limited edition published as a New Year's greeting to friends of the publisher, Harcourt, Brace & World, Inc. Also includes copy in Penguin Books Paperbacks
      - The Columbia University Forum Anthology, P. Spackman and L. Ambrose, eds., 1968 (Box 34)
      - Marko, Vladimir, Russian Futurism: A History, 1968 (Box 34)
      - Mihajlov, Mihajlo, Russian Themes, 1968 (Box 34)
      - Reavey, George, The New Russian Poets 1953-1968: An Anthology (Box 34)
        Inscribed by George Reavey
      - Rowland, Mary F. and Paul, Pasternak's Doctor Zhivago, 1968. (Box 34)
        Paperback
      - The Blind Beauty, Manya Harari and Max Hayward, trans., 1969 (Box 34)
      - Carlyle, Olga, Poets on Street Corners, 1969 (Box 34)
      - Fifty Soviet Poets, V. Ognev, ed., 1969 (Box 34)
      - For Freedom: Theirs and Ours, R. G. Davis-Pointer, ed., 1969 (Box 34)
      - Kataev, Valentin, The Grass of Oblivion, 1969 (Box 34)
      - Miller, A. and I. Morath, In Russia, 1969 (Box 34)
      - Russia's Underground Poets, Keith Bosley et al., trans., 1969 (Box 34)
      - Seven Poems, George Kline, trans., Unicorn Press, 1969. (Box 34)
        Paper and hardback
      - Slepaia krasavitsa, photocopy of typescript for Wm. Collins Sons & Co. Ltd. and Harvill Press, 1969 (Box 34)
      - Troitskii, N., Boris Leonidovich Pasternak: Bibliografiia, Committee on Soviet Studies, Cornell University, 1969 (Box 34)
      - Yarmolinsky, Avram, The Russian Literary Imagination, 1969 (Box 34)
      - Novyi Mir, 1969 April (Box 34)
      - Davie, Donald and Angela Livingstone, Pasternak, 1969-1970 (Box 34)
      - Poems by Boris Pasternak, Eugene Kayden, trans., The Kent State University Press, 1970 (Box 34)
      - Salmagundi, Fall 1970 (Box 34)
      - Fifty Years of Russian Prose, K. Pomorska, ed., 1971 (Box 34)
      - Vukanovich, E., Zvukovaia faktura stikhotvorenii sbornika "Sestra moia zhizn'" – B. L. Pasternaka, Russian Language Journal, 1971 (Box 34)
      - Russian Literature Triquarterly, Fall 1971 (Box 34)
      - Pasternak-Slater, Lydia, Before Sunrise, 1971-1973 and Vspyshki magniia, 1974-1975 (Box 34)
      - Dyck, J. W., Boris Pasternak, 1972 (Box 35)
      - Illness, Lydia Pasternak Slater, trans., Keepsake Press, 1972 (Box 35)
      - Novy Mir: A Selection 1925-1967, Michael Glenny, ed., 1972 (Box 35)
      - Sestra moia zhizn', Ardis facsimile of 1923 Grzhebin edition, 1972 (Box 35)
      - Temy i var'iatsii, Ardis facsimile of 1923 Grzhebin edition, 1972. (Box 35)
      - Russian Literature Triquarterly, Fall 1972; Spring 1973,; and Spring 1974 (Box 35)
      - Gladkov, Aleksandr, Vstrechi s Pasternakom, 1973 (Box 35)
      - Stone, Naomi Burton, Pasternak/Merton: Six Letters, 1958-1960, 1973 (Box 35)
      - The Library Chronicle of the University of Texas at Austin, December 1973 (Box 35)
      - Russian Literature Triquarterly, 1973-1975 (Box 35)
      - Hughes, Olga, The Poetic World of Boris Pasternak, 1974 (Box 35)
      - Livanov, Boris, Risunki i Sharzhi, Iskusstvo, 1974. (Box 35)
      - Post-War Russian Poetry, Daniel Weissbort ed., 1974 (Box 35)
      - Mathewson, Rufus, The Positive Hero in Russian Literature, 1975 (Box 35)
      - Pomorska, Krystyna, Themes and Variations in Pasternak's Poetics, 1975 (Box 35)
      - Barnes, Christopher, ed., Studies in Twentieth Century Russian Literature, 1976 (Box 35)
      - Birnbaum, Henrik, Doktor Faustus und Doktor Schiwago, 1976 (Box 35)
      - Bodin, Per Arne, Nine Poems from Doktor Zivago, Stockholm Studies in Russian Literature, 1976 (Box 35)
      - Freeborn, Richard et al., eds., Russian Literary Attitudes from Pushkin to Solzhenitsyn, 1976 (Box 35)
      - Lazarev, L., Let the Living Remember, 1976 (Box 35)
      - My Sister Life and Other Poems, Olga Carlyle, trans., 1976. (Box 35)
      - Nilsson, Nils Ake, ed., Boris Pasternak Essays, 1976 (Box 35)
      - Vozdushnye puti, Ardis facsimile of 1933 edition, 1976 (Box 35)
      - Stikhotvoreniia i poemy, Biblioteka Poeta, 1976-1977 (Box 35)
      - Collected Prose, Christopher Barnes, ed., 1977. (Box 36)
      - Fleishman, L., Stat'i o Pasternake, K-presse, 1977. (Box 36)
      - Gifford, Henry, Pasternak: A Critical Study, 1977 (Box 36)
      - Poemy, Sovremennik, 1977 (Box 36)
      - Slavica Hierosolymitana, 1977-1978 (Box 36)
      - Ehrlich, Victor, ed., Pasternak: A Collection of Critical Essays, 1978. (Box 36)
      - France, Anna Kay, Boris Pasternak's Translations of Shakespeare, 1978 (Box 36)
      - Gladkov, Alexander, Meetings with Pasternak, 1978. (Box 36)
        Hardback and uncorrected proofs
      - Grashi, Ashot, Rodnik Zhuravlei, 1978 (Box 36)
      - Ivinskaia, Olga, A Captive of Time, 1978. (Box 36)
      - RLT Index 1971-76, 1978 (Box 36)
      - Russian Poetry: The Modern Period, John Glad and Daniel Weissbort, eds., 1978 (Box 36)
      - 1900-1930 Moscou Paris, Centre Georges Pompidou, 1979 (Box 36)
      - Boris Pasternak 1890-1960: Colloque de Cerisy-la-Salle, Institut d'Études Slaves, 1979 (Box 36)
      - Lvov-Rogachevskii, A History of Russian Jewish Literature, Arthur Levin, ed., 1979 (Box 36)
      - Sonata dlia fortepiano, Sovetskii kompozitor, Moscow, 1979 (Box 36)
      - Hosking, Geoffrey, Beyond Socialist Realism, 1980 (Box 37)
      - Krotkov, Yuri, The Nobel Prize, 1980 (Box 37)
      - Berlin, Isaiah, Personal Impressions, the Viking Press, 1981. (Box 37)
      - Fleishman, Lazar, Boris Pasternak v dvatsatye gody, 1981 (Box 37)
      - Hingley, Ronald, Nightingale Fever: Russian Poets in Revolution, 1981 (Box 37)
      - Mallac, Guy de, Boris Pasternak: His Life and Work, 1981 (Box 37)
      - Pasternak, Josephine, Pamiati Pedro, 1981 (Box 37)
      - Perepiska s Ol'goi Freidenberg, Elliott Mossman, ed., 1981 (Box 37)
      - Slepaia krasavitsa, Izdatel'stvo Alagata, Paris, 1981 (Box 37)
      - The Correspondence of Boris Pasternak and Olga Freidenberg 1910-1954, Elliott Mossman, ed., 1982 (Box 37)
      - France, Peter, Poets of Modern Russia, 1982 (Box 37)
      - Selected Poems, Jon Stallworthy and Peter France, trans., 1982. (Box 37)
      - Stikhotvoreniia, Detskaia Literatura, 1982 (Box 37)
      - Vozdushnye puti, Sovetskii Pisatel', 1982. (Box 37)
        Inscribed E. Pasternak
      - Zhenia's Childhood, Allison and Busby, 1982. (Box 37)
        Paperback and hardback
      - Grand Street, vol. 1, no. 4, Summer 1982 (Box 37)
      - Boris Livanov, Vserossiiskoe teatral'noe obshchestvo, 1983 (Box 38)
      - Hayward, Max, Writers in Russia 1917-1978, 1983 (Box 38)
      - I Remember: Sketch for an Autobiography, David Magarshack, trans., 1983 (Box 38)
      - My Sister Life, Mark Rudman and Bohdan Boychuk, trans., 1983. (Box 38)
        Uncorrected proof, hardback and paperback
      - Ozerov, Lev, Neobkhodimost' prekrasnogo, Sovetskii Pisatel', 1983 (Box 38)
      - Pasternak, Aleksandr, Vospominaniia, 1983 (Box 38)
      - Vozdushnye puti, Sovetskii Pisatel', 1983. (Box 38)
        Inscribed by E. Pasternak
      - Hingley, Ronald, Pasternak: A Biography, 1983-1985 (Box 38)
      - Brostrom, Kenneth, ed., Russian Literature and American Critics, 1984 (Box 38)
      - Fleishman, Lazar, Boris Pasternak v tridtsatye gody, 1984. (Box 38)
        Printed copy inscribed by author
      - Gass, Boris, Zadui vo mne svechu, 1984 (Box 38)
      - Kreps, Mikhail, Bukgakov i Pasternak kak romanisty, 1984 (Box 38)
      - Nappelbaum, Moses, Our Age, Ardis, 1984 (Box 38)
      - Poems of Boris Pasternak, Lydia Pasternak Slater, ed., 1984. (Box 38)
      - Selected Poems, Jon Stallworthy and Peter France, trans., 1984 (Box 38)
      - Pasternak, Alexander, A Vanished Present, Ann Pasternak-Slater, trans., 1984-1985 (Box 38)
      - Izbrannoe v dvukh tomakh, Khudozhesvennaia Literatura, 1985 (Box 39)
      - Letters Summer 1926, E. Pasternak et al., eds., 1985 (Box 39)
      - Livingstone, Angela, Pasternak on Art and Creativity, 1985 (Box 39)
      - Triquartely Magazine, 1985 (Box 39)
      - Edel'shtein, Iurii, Pesnopevtsy i proroki, 1986 (Box 39)
      - The Faber Book of Political Verse, Tom Paulen, ed., 1986 (Box 39)
      - Marsh, Rosalind, Soviet Fiction since Stalin: Science, Politics and Literature, 1986 (Box 39)
      - RLT, 1986 (Box 39)
      - Sestra moia zhizn', Alma Ata, 1986 (Box 39)
      - Svecha gorela: Stikhotvoreniia ne voshedshie v osnovnoe sobranie, Orfei, 1986 (Box 39)
      - The Voice of Prose, Christopher Barnes, ed., 1986. (Box 39)
        Hardback and paperback inscribed by the author
      - Bassow, Whitman, The Moscow Correspondents, 1987 (Box 39)
      - Proffer, Carl, The Widows of Russia, 1987 (Box 39)
      - Raine, Craig, The Electrification of the Soviet Union, 1987 (Box 39)
      - Stikhi, 1987. (Box 39)
        Miniature pocket edition
      - Storia di una controttava, Edizioni Studio Tesi, 1987 (Box 39)
      - Voznesenskii, Andrei, An Arrow in the Wall, W. Smith and F. Reeve, eds., 1987 (Box 39)
      - The Zhivago Poems, B. Everest, trans., 1987 (Box 39)
      - V mire knig, May-June 1987 (Box 39)
      - Boris Pasternak: Izbrannaia poeziia, Lazar Fleishman, ed., YMCA-Press, 1988. (Box 40)
      - Feinstein, Elaine, Correspondence Between Pasternak, Tsvetaeva, Rilke: Letters Summer 1926, 1988 (Box 40)
      - Gimpilevich-Shvartsman, Zina, Intelligent v romanakh Doktor Zhivago i Master i Margarita, Antiquary, 1988 (Box 40)
      - Kasack, Wolfgang, Dictionary of Russian Literature Since 1917, 1988 (Box 40)
      - Novyi Mir, vols. 1 and 6, 1988 (Box 40)
      - O'Connor, Katherine Tiernan, Boris Pasternak's My Sister Life: The Illusion of Narrative, 1988 (Box 40)
      - Stikhotvoreniia. Miniature pocket edition, 1988 (Box 40)
      - Stikhotvoreniia i poemy, Khudozhesvennaia Literatura, 1988 (Box 40)
      - Durnye dni, Gefsimanskii sad, 12 stikhotvorenii, avtolitografiia M. Karasika, Leningrad, 1988-1989 (Box 40)
      - Barnes, Christopher, Boris Pasternak: A Literary Biography, 1989 (Box 40)
      - Fleishman, Lazar, ed., Boris Pasternak and His Times: Selected Papers from the Second International Symposium on Pasternak, 1989. (Box 40)
      - Hvezdny dest', Ceskoslovensky spisovatel, 1989 (Box 40)
      - Kaverin, V., Epilog, 1989 (Box 40)
      - Livingstone, Angela, Pasternak: Doctor Zhivago, 1989 (Box 40)
      - Mir Pasternaka, Sovetskii Khudozhnik, 1989 (Box 40)
      - Okhrannaia gramota: Chopin, Sovremennik, Moscow, 1989 (Box 40)
      - Ozerov, Lev, Nachala i kontsy, 1989. (Box 40)
      - Pamiatnye knizhnye daty, Kniga, 1989 (Box 40)
      - Pasternak, Evgenii, Materialy dlia biografii, 1989 (Box 40)
      - Pasternak, Nadezhda, Padcheritsa Boga, 1989 (Box 40)
      - Poesie d'amore, Grandi Tascabili Economici, 1989 (Box 40)
      - RLT, 1989 (Box 40)
      - Soviet Critics on Soviet Literature: The 1980's an Overview, Raduga Publishers, 1989 (Box 40)
      - Stikhi, 1989. (Box 40)
      - Stikhotvoreniia i poemy, A. Voznesenskii et al., eds., 1989 (Box 40)
        vols. 1-3
      - Vil'mont, N., O Borise Pasternake, 1989 (Box 40)
      - Al'fonsov, V., Poeziia Borisa Pasternaka, 1990 (Box 41)
      - Autobiografia, Feltrinelli, 1990 (Box 41)
      - Bakhnov, L., Doktor Zhivago Borisa Pasternaka, 1990 (Box 41)
      - Boris Pasternak ob iskusstve, E. B. and E. V. Pasternak, eds., 1990 (Box 41)
      - Druzhba narodov: Organ Soiuza pisatelei SSSR, 1990 (Box 41)
      - Fleishman, Lazar, The Poet and His Politics, 1990 (Box 41)
      - Gaynor, Elizabeth and Kari Haavisto, Russian Houses, 1990 (Box 41)
      - Iz poezii Borisa Pasternaka, Sovetskii Kompozitor, 1990 (Box 41)
      - Laqueur, Walter, The Long Road to Freedom: Russia and Glasnost', 1990 (Box 41)
      - Levi, Peter, Boris Pasternak, 1990 (Box 41)
      - Maslenikova, Zoia, Portret Borisa Pasternaka, 1990 (Box 41)
      - Moi vzgliad na iskusstvo, 1990 (Box 41)
      - Muravina, Nina, Vstrechi s Pasternakom, 1990 (Box 41)
      - Navrozov, Andrei, Second Nature, 1990 (Box 41)
      - Novo-Basmannaia, 19: 1990, N. Bogomolova, ed. (Box 41)
      - Ozerov, Lev, O Borise Pasternake, 1990 (Box 41)
      - Pasternak, E. V. and E. B., Perepiska Borisa Pasternaka, 1990 (Box 41)
      - Pasternak, E. V. and E. K. Nesterova, Zarubezhnaia poeziia v perevodakh B. L. Pasternaka, 1990 (Box 41)
      - People and Propositions, Chrispher Barnes et al., trans., 1990 (Box 41)
      - Poems, E. Pasternak, ed., 1990 (Box 41)
      - Poems and an Essay in Autobiography, Manya Harari, trans., 1990 (Box 41)
      - Rudiak, Ilya, Twenty Thousand Faces of Pasternak, 1990 (Box 41)
      - Russkie Pisateli: Bibliograficheskii slovar', vols. 1-2, 1990 (Box 41)
      - Selected Writings and Letters, Progress Publishers, 1990 (Box 41)
      - Sommer 1912: Briefe aus Marburg, Marburg, 1990 (Box 41)
      - Soviet Literature, no. 10, 1990 (Box 41)
      - Stikhotvoreniia i poemy, Iu. Andreev et al. eds., 1990 (Box 41)
      - Stikhotvoreniia i poemy: Perevody, L. Ozerov, ed., 1990 (Box 41)
      - Voprosy literatury, Izvestiia, 1990. (Box 41)
        Printed and proof copy
      - Pasternak, E., The Tragic Years 1930-60, 1990-1991 (Box 41)
      - A Centennial Symposium Dedicated to Boris Pasternak, The Russian School of Norwich University, 1991 (Box 42)
      - Detstvo Liuvers, Detskaia Literatura, 1991 (Box 42)
      - Gaynor, Elizabeth and Kari Haavisto, Russian Houses, 1991 (Box 42)
      - Izbrannye proizvedeniia, Panorama, 1991 (Box 42)
      - Muzyka v tvorchestve, sud'be i v dome Borisa Pasternaka, B. A. Kats, 1991 (Box 42)
      - Ne ia pishu stikhi..., E. S. Levitin, ed., 1991 (Box 42)
      - Russkie pisateli-laureaty Nobelevskoi Premii: Boris Pasternak, Moscow, 1991 (Box 42)
      - Sobranie sochinenii, vol. 4, Khudozhestvennaia Literatura, Moscow, 1991 (Box 42)
      - Wolfe, Kurt, A Portrait in Essays and Letters, 1991 (Box 42)
      - Boris Pasternak und Deutschland, Brüder Grimm-Museum Kassel, 1992 (Box 42)
      - "Byt' znamenitym nekrasivo...," Pasternakovskie Chteniia, vypusk 1, Moscow, 1992 (Box 42)
      - Ivinskaia, Olga, Gody s Borisom Pasternakom, Moscow, 1992 (Box 42)
      - My Sister Life, Mark Rudman and Bohdan Boychuk, trans., 1992 (Box 42)
      - Trudnye povesti: 30-e gody, A. Vaniukov, ed., 1992 (Box 42)
      - Boris Pasternak: Peredelkino, 1993 (Box 42)
      - Boris Pasternak: Sochineniia v dvukh tomakh, A. Filippov, ed., 1993 (Box 42)
      - Boris Pasternak: Vtoroe Rozhdenie: Pis'ma k Z. N. Pasternak. Z. N. Pasternak: Vospominaniia, N. Pasternak and M. Feinberg, eds., 1993 (Box 42)
      - Carlyle, Olga, Under a New Sky, 1993 (Box 42)
      - Fleishman, Lazar, Boris Pasternak, il Mulino, 1993 (Box 42)
      - Gordeev, V., B. Pasternak: So mnoi..., 1993 (Box 42)